Dear Kagura-chan:
(星海坊主)｢拝啓 神楽ちゃん
元気にやってますか？
How have you been?
お父さんのほうは
毛根は死滅しましたが➡
All my hair follicles have died, but otherwise, I'm okay.
体は元気です｡
えいりあんを追って
星々を飛び回る生活は➡
As usual, I'm flying through the stars chasing Aliens.
相変わらずですが
最近は どこだかの星の➡
Lately, I've been mixed up in a battle
[Note: Earth Federation is a GUNDAM parody]
連邦軍と 公国軍の戦いに
巻き込まれて 結構 忙しいです｣
between the Earth Federation and The Principality on a planet somewhere.
(赤い人)ｷｻﾏ ただ者ではないな｡
ﾆｭｰﾀｲﾌﾟか？
You're no ordinary guy, I take it. Are you a new type?
(星海坊主)こないだまで
頭頂ﾀｲﾌﾟだったんだが➡
Until a while back, I was a haired-type, but now I'm a skin-type.
[Note: A parody of GUNDAM's zuchou vs. zentou type]
今は 全頭ﾀｲﾌﾟだ｡
いや 冗談ではない｡
No, that's not what I meant...
(星海坊主)｢まぁ
お父さんが ついたからには➡
Anyway, now that I'm here, The Principality will win.
間違いなく
公国軍が勝つと思います｣
おい！ 今日から ｵﾚが
公国を指揮するから➡
Listen up! As of today, I will be in command of the Federated Army!
とりあえず全員 坊主な！
Everyone will shave their heads! Grow long hair and I will whack your ass!
ﾁｬﾗﾁｬﾗ 髪の伸ばすﾔﾂは ｹﾂﾊﾞｯﾄな！
(星海坊主)｢それより神楽ちゃんは
楽しくやってますか？
More importantly, are you enjoying yourself, Kagura-chan?
あの銀髪に いじめられたり➡
Is that silver-haired guy bullying you,
あのﾒｶﾞﾈに
思春期特有の いやらしい目で➡
or that four-eyed guy looking at you with those lecherous eyes you only see on adolescents?
見られたり していませんか？｣
(星海坊主)娘がさ
地球に留学しててさ｡
My daughter is studying abroad on Earth.
(赤い人)ﾏｼﾞでか？
それは心配だな｡
Seriously? You must be worried.
(星海坊主)｢何かあったら
気軽に手紙ください｡
If anything is wrong, just let me know. Daddy will come and kill them all.
お父さんが皆殺しに行きます｡
それじゃあ また手紙します｣
Good-bye. I'll write again.
(星海坊主)｢P.S. １つ
言い忘れていたことがあった｡
P.S.: I forget to say one thing.
神楽ちゃんたちが飼っていた
あの でかい犬な…｡
It's about that big dog you're keeping... You should really dump it before it turns into a monster.
あれ とんでもないﾊﾞｹﾓﾉだから
すぐに捨てなさい｣
(神楽)今頃 遅えんだよ ﾊｹﾞが｡
You're too late...baldy.
それに 何て言われたって➡
And besides, no matter what anyone says, I'm never leaving you.
絶対 離れないｱﾙよ｡ ねぇ 定春？
(定春)ﾜﾝｯ！
Right, Sadaharu?
[Thank you to Sasaki-kun, Sekiba-kun, Nakajima-kun and Arai-kun of Sendai for the photo. That's a near perfect ice rendition of the Neo-Armstrong cannon.]
[But don't expect a gift; the world isn't that generous. You can have the gift of a "memory in your hearts" because we showed it on TV.]
So you see, the game scheduled for the dome was cancelled.
(阿音)それでさぁ 結局ﾄﾞｰﾑで
やるはずだった野球の試合は中止｡
その賠償金も
ｳﾁが払うことになっちゃって➡
And to pay off all the damage we had to sell all our shrine property.
神社 売り飛ばしちゃったのよ｡
Oh my!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)あら～｡
(阿音)ﾎﾝﾄ やってらんないわよ｡
I can't believe we have to go through all this just because of a dog.
たかが 犬１匹のためにさぁ｡
And now, my younger sister and I are back to living in an apartment.
また 妹とｱﾊﾟｰﾄ暮らしよ｡
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)だからさぁ
男も犬も 一緒なのよ｡
That's why men are just like dogs.
身勝手に捨てると いつか
そうやって復讐されるのよ｡
You dump 'em without a second thought, but they eventually come back to bite you.
(阿音)男は大丈夫よ
犬より ﾊﾞｶな生き物だから｡
Yeah, but at least dogs are smarter.
(黒服)阿音ちゃん
指名 入りました～｡
Ane-san, you've been requested. Table 3.
３番ﾃｰﾌﾞﾙで～す｡
Coming.
(阿音)は～い｡
Is it Mr. Kikuya again? That lech really likes you.
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)また 菊屋の旦那？
好きねぇ あのｴﾛｼﾞｼﾞｲも｡
Like I said, they always come back.
(阿音)ねぇ
だから言ったでしょう？
ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊﾞｶよね 巫女っていうだけで
みんな ﾒﾛﾒﾛなんだから｡
They're really stupid. They get so worked up just because I'm a miko.
(阿音)ﾅｰｽに 巫女に ｽﾁｭﾜｰﾃﾞｽ｡
Nurses, miko, and flight attendants... The insane fantasies they have about women.
女に 神聖な幻想でも
抱いてんのかしら｡
If they only knew that being a woman meant spending you life battling through piles of crap.
(阿音)女なんて みんな
肥だめから生まれてきてんの｡
銀ﾊﾞｴの飛び交うなか
戦ってんのよ｡
(店内の ざわめき)
["Adults Only. We Wouldn't Want Anyone Immature in Here..."]
(ざわめき)
Boss, it's me, Ane. I'm so glad you came to s-
旦那～ 阿音だよ！
また会いにきて…｡
(菊屋の うめき声)
(お妙)あっ阿音ちゃんが
来ましたよ 菊屋の旦那｡
Ane-chan's here, Boss Kikuya.
なにしてんの ｱﾝﾀ～！
What the hell are you doing?!
I was filling in for you 'til you showed up, Ane-chan.
阿音ちゃんが来るまで
ﾍﾙﾌﾟに入ってたんだけど➡
急に お尻 触られたものだから➡
But the jerk grabbed my butt. I was startled, and...
ﾋﾞｯｸﾘして～｡
(阿音)こっちが ﾋﾞｯｸﾘだわ！
I'm the one who's startled! What're you doing to my customer?!
ｱﾝﾀ 私の客に
なにしてくれてんのよ～！
I'm sorry. He's not my customer, so I figured it's okay.
ごめんなさい 私の客じゃないし
いいかなって思って｡
You know damn well it isn't!
いいわけねえだろ！
私なりの 接客ﾃｸﾆｯｸなんだけど｡
It's my way of welcoming a customer.
Look, just because that gorilla, who's always stalking you, doesn't mind being beaten up,
ｱﾝﾀ 自分の客のｺﾞﾘﾗｽﾄｰｶｰ
いつも ﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺにしてるからって➡
誰にでも 通用すると思ったら
大間違いだぞ～！
that doesn't mean you can treat anyone else that way!
Who're you calling a stalker gorilla! That's rude, you!
(近藤)誰が ｺﾞﾘﾗｽﾄｰｶｰだ！
失敬だぞ ｷﾐ～!!
お妙さん ちょっと
ﾋﾞｼｯと言ってやってください！
Otae-san, tell her off.
All right...get lost, gorilla.
わかりました
消え去りなさい ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
えっ いや そうじゃなくて｡
No, that's not what I meant.
If you don't want to hear it, get out of here, gorilla.
この世に 一片の細胞も残さずに
消え去りなさい ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
いや そうじゃなくて！
No, that's not what I meant.
In fact, do the world a favor and get out of everywhere, gorilla.
ついでに 関わった人間
すべての記憶から➡
その存在を消し去りなさい ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
ｸ～ そうじゃなくて…｡
No, that's not what I meant.
(おりょう)ちょっと
落ちついてよ 阿音｡
Just a minute, calm down, Ane. You're shocking the other customers.
他のお客さんが驚いてるよ｡
Otae definitely went too far, but Mr. Kikuya is also at fault.
確かに お妙も やり過ぎだけど
菊屋の旦那も 悪いのよ｡
He keeps trying to turn this place into an all-you-can-grope buffet.
お触りﾊﾟﾌﾞと
勘違いしてるﾌｼがあって➡
店の他の娘も
みんな嫌がってんのよ｡
The other hostesses don't like him, either.
ｹﾂ～？
Your butt?
What's the big deal about getting your butt groped?
ｹﾂ 触られたくらいで
あんだっつうのよ！
ｹﾂが なんで
２つに割れてるか知ってる？
Do you know why there are two halves to your butt?
It's so that you won't mind if someone touches one half.
それは 片方 触られても
平気なようによ｡
いや 違うと思う｡
No, I don't think so.
If he touches your left cheek, let him touch your right!
左のｹﾂを 触られたら
右のｹﾂも 触らせる！
Everyone knows that you're supposed to turn the other cheek!
常識よ！
違うわ｡
Ridiculous! Our butt cheeks are vestiges of when we were all angels. They were once wings.
お尻はね 人間が昔
天使だった頃の名残なのよ｡
翼だったの｡
それも ちょっと…｡
Now that's ridiculous!
What's with that? You being romantic? Like we were some kind of magic girl?
なに それ？ ﾛﾏﾝﾁｯｸなつもり？
今どき 不思議ちゃんｷｬﾗ？
じゃあ➡
Yeah! Boobs used to be wings!
ﾁﾁなら どうじゃ～！ ｸﾞｯ｡
うおぉ～！
(菊屋)うぅ…｡
You got it wrong, Pal. They're left over from when we used to be living arsenals.
胸もﾀﾞﾒです｡ 胸は 人間が昔➡
古代兵器だった頃の名残なのよ｡
ﾐｻｲﾙなの｡
They were missiles.
最終的に 人間って何だったのよ！
Just what do you think humans used to be?
Okay, I'm not running a Touchy Pub here. But it's not an S&M bar, either, okay.
(店長)いやいや 確かにね
ｳﾁは お触りﾊﾟﾌﾞではないです｡
でもね ＳＭｸﾗﾌﾞでもないからね｡
This isn't the place for enjoying sadistic shows.
ｻﾃﾞｨｽﾃｨｯｸなﾌﾟﾚｲを
楽しむところでもないからね｡
(お妙/阿音)そうですね｡
(店長)そうですねって➡
Yes, you're right.
"Yes, you're right"?! What is this, the Kazuyoshi Morita hour?
[Note: A play off Kazuyoshi Morita who is Tamori, the basis for the Tamo-san in this series]
森田 一義ｱﾜｰでもないからね
ここは｡
(お妙/阿音)そうですね｡
Yes, you're right.
You two make me so mad...
腹立つな ｺｲﾂら…｡
So, Otae-chan,
でさ お妙ちゃんさ➡
確かに ｷﾐには
ﾀﾁの悪い酔っ払いを 追い払う➡
I did ask for you to do a little bouncer duty on our worst drunks,
用心棒的なことも 頼んでたけど➡
最近 やり過ぎだから
用心棒にしても｡
but I think you've gone too far with the stick.
ﾎﾞｰじゃないです ｱﾅです｡
I don't have a stick, I have a hole.
[Note: A play on the word, bou = stick/rod and youjinbou＝bouncer/bodyguard]
No, that’s not the issue here. Women shouldn’t say such things.
(店長)いや
そういう問題じゃないからね｡
女の子が そんなことを言ったら
ﾀﾞﾒだからね｡
And as for you, Ane-chan, I realize you need money,
それから 阿音ちゃん ｷﾐはね➡
お金が欲しいのは わかるけど➡
but your methods are a bit unscrupulous.
やり方が
ちょっと あざとすぎるね｡
I’ve received many complaints from customers
お客さんから
いっぱい苦情が来てね｡
さんざん 貢がされたあげく
捨てられたって｡
that you dumped them after they’d given you every cent in their wallets.
I haven’t dumped them. I recycle the men who can save up enough money to crawl back to me.
捨ててません｡ また お金を貯めて
はい上がってきた男たちは➡
ﾘｻｲｸﾙするつもりです｡
I never heard of such a nasty recycling that was so harsh on the Earth.
(店長)そんな地球に厳しいﾘｻｲｸﾙ
聞いたことないからね｡
(店長)まぁね ２人とも
ｳﾁの店では 売れっ娘だし➡
Well, the two of you are the top girls here. I’d really like to keep you both…
ﾎﾝﾄはね 温かい目で
見守っていきたいんだけれども｡
but this business is not going to survive with two nuclear warheads here at the same time.
核弾頭 ２つ所持して
やっていけるほど➡
甘くないから この世界｡
That’s why I need one of you to quit by the end of this month.
だから どっちか１人
店やめてもらうから｡
The one who’ll remain is…
(店長)残ってもらうのは…
そうだね➡
Well, it’s just about the day when we tally monthly sales,
明日 ちょうど今月の
売り上げが出る日だから➡
利益を上げたほうに
残ってもらおうと思うよ｡
so I think the one who brings in more sales will stay.
《阿音:冗談じゃないわよ｡
生活が苦しくなって➡
He can’t be serious.
At a time when I’m already struggling to make a living and have to work even harder.
これから
がんばらなきゃってときに｡
ﾁｯ いまいましい女だわ｡
Damn that hateful woman.
私の客が いったい何人
あの女の犠牲になったことか｡
Who knows how many of my customers have been her victim.
売り上げなんて
私の足元にも及ばないくせに➡
She’s never sold as many drinks as I have. And yet everyone adores her.
妙に みんなに慕われてて｡
そういうところも
前から気にくわなかったのよ｡
I’ve never liked that about her.
これを機に
店から追い払ってやるわ》
This is the perfect chance to drive her out of the bar!
Ane-chan.
(お妙)阿音ちゃん｡
(お妙)
なんか大変なことになったわね｡
I’ve gotten out of hand. I’m sorry. It seems I got us into it this whole mess.
ごめんなさい
私が火種になっちゃったみたいで｡
《ﾌﾝ ｱﾝﾀの手の内は
読めてるのよ》
I see what you’re doing.
気にしちゃいないわよ｡
I’m not blaming you. Let’s both try our best tomorrow.
まぁ お互い
明日は がんばりましょう｡
《油断させようったって
そうはいかないわ》
I’m not letting you give me a false sense of security.
その勝負なんだけど…➡
About our contest… I’ll forfeit.
私は 降りさせてもらいます｡
えっ？
みんなから聞いたわ｡
I heard from everyone.
Ane-chan, they said you had to abandon the shrine you were living in and how it’s been really difficult .
阿音ちゃん
住んでた神社も売り払って➡
すごい苦労してるって｡
And on top of that, you’re looking after your introverted younger sister.
そのうえ
ひきこもりの妹さんの面倒も➡
みてるんでしょ？
I…can’t fight against you, Ane-chan.
私… 阿音ちゃんとは戦えない｡
I know. I know that you work harder than anyone, Ane-chan.
私 知ってるから｡
阿音ちゃんが 誰よりも
一生懸命 働いてたこと｡
がんばってね｡ 応援してるから｡
Hang in there. I’m rooting for you.
What just happened?
《なんなのよ…》
That caught me totally off guard. That woman doesn’t make any sense. But…
《拍子抜けだわ｡
わけのわからない女｡
でも…➡
I think I understand why everyone likes her so much.
どうして あの女が
みんなに慕われてるか➡
少～しだけ わかった気がする》
(店員)いらっしゃいませ～｡
２名様で？
Welcome. Two?
(長谷川)
こ… ここで いいんだよな？
This the place? You’re sure this is the right place?
この店で合ってんだよな？
(銀時)おいおい
高えんじゃねえの？ 大丈夫かよ｡
Hey, hey. Isn’t this place expensive? You sure it’s okay?
ﾌﾌｯ… あっ！
(阿音)ｱﾝﾀ 万事屋の！
You’re from the Odd Jobs!
The miko hussy. You’re working here, too?!
あ ｱﾊﾞｽﾞﾚ巫女｡
お前も ここで働いてたの？
Who’re you calling a hussy? What’re you doing here?!
誰が ｱﾊﾞｽﾞﾚよ！
ｱﾝﾀ なんで こんなとこにいんの？
Huh? I know someone here.
ん？ ちょっと 知り合いがね｡
Sir, shall I call a particular girl?
(ﾎﾞｰｲ)お客様 ご指名は？
お妙ちゃん 頼むわ｡
Call Otae-chan.
お…｡
O…!
Gin-san, Hasegawa-san. Right this way.
銀さ～ん 長谷川さ～ん
こっちで～す｡
That bitch! She called her customers here!
《阿音:あのｱﾏ～！ 客に
呼び込み かけてやがったぁ!!》
Hot, hot, hot!
It’s been so long time since I’ve been in a place like this.
いやぁ こんなとこ 久しぶりだぜ｡
Hey, you’re gonna give us a deal, right?
おい ﾎﾝﾄに
ｻｰﾋﾞｽしてくれんだろうな？
あんま 金ねえぞ｡
We haven’t got much money.
((お妙:阿音ちゃん
借金で すごい苦労してるって｡
Ane-chan says she’s really struggling to pay back what she borrowed.
(お妙)私…
阿音ちゃんとは戦えない))
I…can’t compete with Ane-chan.
《お妙:な～んてね｡
Or so I want you to believe.
I couldn’t care less what happens to you. I have my own oath to restore my father’s dojo.
そっちが どうなろうが
知ったこっちゃないわ｡
私には 父上の道場を
再興するという悲願があるのよ》
She tricked me! How could I have missed that?!
《阿音:やられたぁ…
私としたことが！
あのｱﾏ～!!》
That bitch!
♪♪～
[Teach me! Ginpachi Sensei]
[Question Corner]
[Ginpachi Sakata]
え～ ｱﾆﾒｰﾀｰになって
『銀魂』を描きたいっ子さん より｡
This is from “I want to be an animator and draw Gin Tama.”
I can’t seem to draw Gin-san’s hair well. Please give me just a small hint.
｢銀さんの髪型が
どうしても うまく描けません｡
ちょっとしたｺﾂでよいので
教えてください｣
All right, I’ll teach you.
はい それじゃあ
お教えしましょう｡
His hair may appear random, but it does follow some rules.
ﾔﾂの頭は 一見 ﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒに見えて
法則性があります｡
[How to draw Gin-san]
ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄは ４か所の逆毛です｡
The key is the four cowlicks.
まず まともな頭を描きましょう｡
First, draw a normal head.
Then, draw small cowlicks on both sides of the top of his head.
で 次に
この まともな頭の頭頂部の➡
ちょいと右と左
両方に 逆毛を作ります｡
Then draw cowlicks around the ears and elongate the front hair and you’re done.
で 耳のあたりにも 逆毛を作り➡
前髪ど真ん中を
ﾋﾞｭｰｯと伸ばせば➡
[Done.]
はい｡
Just so you know, anime is a tough job that doesn’t make much money, so I wouldn’t recommend it.
ちなみに ｱﾆﾒは つらいうえに
儲からない仕事なんで➡
先生は あまり勧めないけどな｡
[Teach me! Ginpachi Sensei]
じゃあ さっきは
銀さんの描き方を教えたんで➡
Okay, now that I’ve taught you how to draw Gin-san, let’s do Shinpachi and Kagura next.
次は 新八と神楽を｡
まず
思うがままに普通のﾔﾂを描きます｡
[How to draw Shinpachi]
First draw what you think is a ordinary guy. Make it lack as much personality as possible.
できるだけ 没個性的な｡
Then, give it glasses. Okay… Done.
で ﾒｶﾞﾈを かけます
はい｡
[Done]
Next, how to draw Kagura.
[How to draw Kagura]
続いて
神楽の描き方｡
First, remove Shinpachi’s glasses, and make the hair white.
まず 新八の
ﾒｶﾞﾈを取り 髪を白くします｡
で 頭に
おだんごを作ります｡
Next, add two buns on the head. Okay…Done.
はい｡
[Done.]
All the characters are based on Shinpachi.
あらゆるｷｬﾗは
新八ﾍﾞｰｽから できています｡
新八をﾏｽﾀｰすれば いろんなｷｬﾗを
描くことができるぞ｡
If you master Shinpachi, you can draw all the characters! So, let’s Shinpachi!
さぁ ﾚｯﾂ 新八！
♪♪～
《阿音:や やられたぁ…
私としたことが！》
She tricked me! How could I have missed that?!
《ﾌｯﾌｯﾌｯ…》
That bitch!
《あのｱﾏ～！
ｸｿがぁっ!!
Shit.
It’s still not too late.
今からでも間に合うかぁ!?》
(ｹｰﾀｲのﾌﾟｯｼｭ音)
Hi, I’m Oryo. Cool shades!
うぃ～っす おりょうです｡
わっ かっこいいｸﾞﾗｻﾝ！
What? You can tell? Actually, they were expensive.
えっ わかる？
高かったんだよ これ 実は｡
とりあえず なに？
So what do we do now? Can I touch your butt?
ｹﾂとか触っていいの？
ふっ！
じょ 冗談だよ｡
お前の貧相なｹﾂ 触るくらいなら➡
Just kidding. I’d be better off kneading dough than grabbing your flat behind.
小麦粉 ﾆﾁｬﾆﾁｬ練り続けたほうが
まだﾏｼだ｡
Oh? You’re so turned on your nose is bleeding.
どうだか｡
鼻血なんて たらして いやらしい｡
Incredible. She’s already forgotten what happened two frames ago.
すごいや この人｡
２ｶｯﾄ前のこと もう忘れてるよ｡
Such a fun customer you are. Would you like a drink?
楽しい お客さ～ん｡
とりあえず 何 飲みます？
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘとか あと… そうねぇ➡
We have Dom-Peri and…Dom-Peri and Dom-Peri and Dom-Peri.
[Note: Dom-Peri is Japanese for Dom Perignon]
[Dom-Peri Dom-Peri Dom-Peri Dom-Peri]
[Note: written with various forms of “don”]
丼ﾍﾟﾘとか
呑ﾍﾟﾘとか ﾄﾞﾝ減りとか あるけど｡
焼酎 水割り｡
わかりました｡
[Shochu and water]
Shochu and water.
You got it.
Dom-Peri, please!
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ お願いしま～す！
Somebody, call an interpreter!
誰か～！ 通訳 呼んでくれ!!
Dom-Peri? Brings back memories of when I worked for the Bakufu and they’d serve it at elite events.
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘかぁ 懐かしいな｡
幕府にいた頃は
接待とかで よく飲んだよ｡
It’s too expensive to pay out of my own pocket, so I never touched the stuff.
自腹じゃ 高すぎて
手が出ねえけどな｡
なんか もっと安いのでいいよ｡
ﾋﾞｰﾙとかさ｡
We’ll be fine with something cheaper. Like beer.
(長谷川)え～と…｡
Dom-Peri…Dom-Peri mixed with Dom-Peri, not beer but Dom-Peri, Dom-Peri.
Nothing but Dom-Per. More Dom-Peri. Say Dom-Peri. What?
What was Dom-Peri? I’m all mixed up. Dom-Peri.
(２人)ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘしかねぇ～っ!!
It’s all Dom-Peri!
ぼったくりだ｡ 間違いねえ
ぼったくりﾊﾞｰだよ ここ｡
They’re ripping us off. No doubt about it. This is a rip-off joint!
That’s ridiculous. Otae-chan wouldn’t do a thing like that.
ﾊﾞｶな｡
お妙ちゃんに限って そんな…｡
Then what’s a Dom-Peri mixed with Dom-Peri?
だって
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘのﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ割りって 何だよ｡
割り切れねえよ｡ ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘも
ｵﾚの気持も 割り切れねえよ｡
I can’t understand that. I don’t understand all this Dom-Peri or my own thoughts.
Gin-san.
(お妙)銀さん｡
You and I haven’t had Dom-Peri in a while.
私 久しぶりに
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘが飲みたいﾄﾞﾝ｡
ﾄﾞﾝって 太鼓ｹﾞｰﾑ？
Dom? Is that like beating a drum? What? When did we ever have Dom Perignon?
なに 久しぶりって
飲ましたことねえよ そんなもん！
長谷川さんのｸﾞﾗｻﾝとか
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝとか ｸﾞﾗｻﾝとか➡
Hasegawa-san, I think your shades, and your shades, and your shades
would go well with Dom-Peri.
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘと合うと思うんだけどな ﾍﾟﾘ｡
ﾍﾟﾘ!?
Peri?!
おかしい！ おかしいよ！
That’s odd! You’re odd! Are my shades the only thing you can compliment?!
ってか 褒めるとこ
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝしかねえのか!?
Please, Dom.
お願いﾄﾞﾝ｡
飲みたいﾍﾟﾘ｡
I want to drink it, Peri.
いいﾄﾞﾝ？
ねぇﾍﾟﾘ？
All right, Dom?
Okay, Peri?
おいおい おいおい！
語尾 ２人 合わせたら➡
Hey, hey, hey. Put it together and it’s Dom-Peri.
Dom-Peri! Dom-Peri!
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘになっちゃったよ！
Subliminal advertising!
ｻﾌﾞﾘﾐﾅﾙ？ ｻﾌﾞﾘﾐﾅﾙかぁ!?
They’re manipulating our subconscious minds! Cover your ears! Don’t let them sway you!
ｵﾚたちの深層心理に
直接 働きかけるつもりか!?
耳を ふさげ！ 惑わされるな!!
Excuse me. Five Dom-Peri please!
すみません ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ５本 お願いﾄﾞﾝ！
だぁ～っ!!
ぐぉっ!!
(歓声)
It’s Big Daddy Matsudaira!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)松平の旦那よ！
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たち)まっちゃん！
Macchan!! Macchan!! Macchan!!
Oh “Daddy”, I’m so happy you could make it!
ﾊﾟﾊﾟ！ 嬉しいわ
ﾎﾝﾄに来てくれたのね～｡
Forgive me, I pulled you away from work.
ごめんね 仕事中だったんでしょ？
(松平)いいんだよ あんな会議｡
It’s all right. It was just a meeting.
江戸が
滅亡するわけでもあるめえし｡
Not like Edo’s going to be destroyed or anything.
でも おじさんは
ここに来ないと 滅亡するからね｡
But if I can’t come here, I will be destroyed.
Oh you make me so happy!
やぁ～ 嬉しい～｡
That’s Big Daddy Matsudaira!
あれは 松平の旦那！
ﾏｼﾞかよ｡
Really?
(おりょう)お妙！ あのおっさん➡
Otae! That man is famous for the outrageously extravagant way he parties.
遊び方が とんでもなく派手で
有名なのよ！
“Daddy.” I haven’t had Dom-Peri in a while.
ﾊﾟﾊﾟ～
私 久しぶりに ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ 飲みた～い｡
That stuff’s like juice. I’d like to drink something stronger, but ah well…
(松平)
あんなもん ｼﾞｭｰｽじゃねえか！
おじさん もっともっと きついの
飲みたいんだけどなぁ～｡
まぁ ええか…｡
Five Dom-Peri, coming right up!
(ﾎﾞｰｲ)ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ５本 入りま～す｡
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たちの歓声)
(ﾎﾞｰｲ)さっそく ついじゃいます！
I’ll serve it right away.
What a waste! It’s spilling over.
もったいねえ～
こぼれちまってるよ｡
ﾎｽﾄｸﾗﾌﾞ並みね｡
It’s like at a host club.
Cheers!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たち)乾杯！
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たち)ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ…！
Chug, Chug…!
(歓声)
Big Daddy, you’re wonderful.
(阿音)わぁ～！ ｽﾃｷ～!!
My gosh, five bottles at once… There’s no way you can win against that…
ﾊﾊｯ… 一気に５本
こんなの勝ち目が…｡
What? You want to beat him?
なに？ あれに勝ちたいの？
Hell, we can match every one of their champagnes with 80-20 water and shochu and get higher than him.
心配しなくても ｵﾚたち
水と焼酎 ８:２の水割りで➡
あれより ﾊｲになれんぜ！
That’s not what this battle is about. She doesn’t want such a lame victory.
そんな戦いじゃないから！
そんな悲しい勝利 いらないから｡
《ﾌﾌﾌ… 見た？
Did you see that? This is the difference between you and I.
これが
あなたと私の手駒の違いよ》
Otae, what’ll you do? At this rate…
お妙 どうする？ このままじゃ…｡
Is it okay to let her get on that kind of a roll?
(おりょう)ｱｲﾂらを
調子づかせていいの？
(近藤)おいおい ｷﾐたち！
なんてｼｹた面してんだ!!
Hey, hey, you guys, why the long faces?
Bring 10 bottles of Dom Perignon.
(近藤)ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾙｰﾆｮ10本 持ってこい！
近藤さん！
Kondo-san!
We have an order for 10 Dom-Peri!
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ10本 入りま～す！
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たちの歓声)
♪♪～
(店長)よっしゃ よっしゃ…｡
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)ｷｬ～！ すごいわ!!
Awesome!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢)一気に お妙ちゃんが
阿音ちゃんを抜いたわ！
Otae-chan jumped ahead of Ane-chan all at once!
なに!?
What?!
I heard what’s going on from the hostesses.
店の女の娘から
事情は聞きました｡
You could’ve come to me, Otae-san.
お妙さん
水くさいじゃありませんか｡
ｵﾚの預金通帳は
すでに夫婦のものとして➡
I’ve been saving up my savings passbook as a joint account for when we’re married.
お妙さんと
共同名義になってるんですよ｡
[O-Edo Bank Passbook]
You can relax now. I may not look it, but I’ve made quite a lot.
もう安心してください｡
こう見えても
結構 稼いでますから！
ｺﾞﾘﾗさん…｡
…Gorilla-san.
Don’t call me G-Gorilla… It doesn’t match this scene.
ｺﾞ… ｺﾞﾘﾗはないよね…
このｼｰﾝで ｺﾞﾘﾗは｡
じゃあ ｺﾞﾘﾗｯさん｡
Okay…Go-rilla-san.
Same thing.
同じだよ…｡
(松平)近藤～!!
Kondo!
ﾃﾒｴ このかぶき町で
ｵﾚより目立とうなんざ➡
You’re a hundred years too early to try and outshine me in Kabukicho!
百年 早いんだよ～！
うるせえ～ ｴﾛｼﾞｼﾞｲ！
Shut up, lecherous old man! From tonight on, I am the King of Nightlife!
今日から
夜の帝王は このｵﾚだ～！
Don’t be ridiculous! I won’t allow even the Shogun to take away what I live for! 15 Dom-Peri!
ふざけるな～！
ｵﾚの生きがいを奪うﾔﾂは➡
たとえ将軍でも許さねえ！
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ15本だ～!!
ｷｬ～!! ﾊﾟﾊﾟ かっこいい～！
You’re so cool, Daddy!
お妙さん！ こっちもﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟ…｡
Otae-san! Dom-Peri over here, too…
Excuse me. Another round of Dom-Peri with this.
(お妙)すみませ～ん
これで ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ おかわり！
You mean you already ordered? That’s my wallet! Nobody said “you’re so cool!”
…って もう頼んでるし！
それ ｵﾚの財布だし!!
｢かっこいい～｣とかないし！
いやいや かっこいいよ お前！
ｵﾚら ちゃんとわかってるって!!
No, you’re terrific, guy. We all know that.
なかなか こんな貢げないよ｡
It’s not easy to give as much as you did. Gorilla, you’re one heck of a guerilla!
ｺﾞﾘﾗが ｶﾞｯﾘｰﾗに見えるよ｡
ｱﾙﾌｧﾍﾞｯﾄに
変わっただけじゃねえか！
All you did was change the spelling!
ってか 店の娘でもないお前らが
なんで飲んでるの!?
Why are you drinking when you’re not even part of the staff?
こまかいことは気にすんな！
(長谷川)すんな～!!
Don’t worry about the details!
Don’t!
I do!
(近藤)するよ！
(お妙)ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ追加!!
More Dom-Peri!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たち)
ｷｬ～！ 過去最高記録だわ!!
This is a record!
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ おかわり！
ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ もう一丁!!
Another round of Dom-Peri!
Another Dom-Peri!
まだ まだ ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ！
Keep the Dom-Peri coming!
どんどん ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘ！
More and more Dom-Peri!
(ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢たち)
わぁ～ ものすごいﾃﾞｯﾄﾞﾋｰﾄ!!
It’s neck to neck!
おいしいよ おいしいよ！
もっと もっと!!
Drink up!
さぁ どうぞ… どうぞ どうぞ！
ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ～！ やるな… 近藤｡
You’re pretty good, Kondo. But isn’t your wallet nearly drained by now?
だが そろそろ財布のほうが
やばくなってんじゃねえのか？
ﾍｯ… 甘くみるなよ！
ｵﾚは 夫婦貯金をすべておろして｡
Don’t underestimate me. I withdrew my entire marriage savings.
あれ？ もうねえじゃん！
どういうこと!?
Huh?! There’s nothing left. What’s going on?
ﾌﾌﾊﾊｯ… ﾃﾒｴは ﾄﾞﾝﾍﾟﾘなんざ➡
You never ordered Dom Perignon on your own so you didn’t know!
めったに頼んだことねえから
知らねえだろ｡
あれ ﾏｼﾞで高えんだぞ！
ﾎﾝﾄ 高えんだぞ!!
It’s staggeringly expensive! It really is. It’s expensive!
A few dozen glasses of it can wipe out your savings!
ﾀﾞｰｽ単位で買ってたら
金なんか すぐなくならぁ｡
ﾌﾊﾊﾊ… どうしよう
かあちゃんに怒られる～！
"What’ll I do? My wife’s gonna kill me!"
って お前も やばいのかい!?
So you’re finished, too!
やばい… お妙さん｡
Uh-oh, Otae-san…
近藤さん もういいです｡
Kondo-san, that’s enough. What you’ve done is plenty…
ここまで やってくれただけで…｡
お妙さん｡
Otae-san…
ﾋｯｸ… あとは これを➡
Now all you have to do is sell this and that’ll be enough…
売っぱらってくれれば
十分ですから｡
Um…sell that? But, that’s a Samurai’s soul.
(近藤)あの 売っぱらってって➡
それは
武士の魂なんですけど… 一応｡
Soul? You can just buy a new one.
(お妙)魂なんて
また買えばいいじゃないですか！
(近藤)いや そういうわけにも…｡
No, I can’t do that.
(お妙)ﾋﾞｯｸﾞﾏﾈｰ
たたきつけてくださいよ！
Let’s see some big money!
She’s right. She’s right.
そうだ そうだ！
いるなら 中古で買え!!
If you need one, buy it used! I bought mine from an infomercial!
ｵﾚなんて
通販で 刀 買ってんだよ！
えぇ!? お前 ﾏｼﾞで 仙人に
もらったとか言ってなかった？
What? You said you bought it from a wizard.
それ ｳｯｿ～！
うわっ ひでえ!!
I lied!
That’s awful.
ｵﾚなんか これ
ちゃんと 本店 行って➡
I went to the main store, and anguished and anguished before…
迷って迷って もう…｡
(お妙)お前は ｸﾞﾗｻﾝな！
You sell your shades.
えっ？
だから ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ 売ってこいって…｡
What…
I said, go sell your shades.
And buy me a drink!
(お妙)言ってんだよ～！
うわぁ～！
高えんだろ？
They’re expensive, aren’t they?
いけ！
Get going!
ｳﾊﾊﾊ…！
貧乏なくせに見栄張って➡
That’s what you get for trying to act cool when you’re dirt broke!
高いもん 身につけてるから
そういう目に遭うんだよ！
ｵﾚを見ろ！
日頃 質素に生きてるから➡
Look at me! I live simply, so I’ve got nothing to lose.
失うものなんて何も…｡
(お妙)お前は借りてこい！
You, go borrow money.
だから 金持ってねえﾔﾂは
借りてこいって言ってんだよ！
I’m saying, guys who don’t have any money need to go borrow some!
(長谷川/銀時)いっ…｡
(松平)ｸｯｸｯｸｯ…｡
That’s why I said you punks are a hundred years too young to be playing at night.
だから ｶﾞｷが夜遊びなんて
百年 早えっつうんだよ｡
引き際を知らねえｶﾞｷは
この街じゃ生きていけねえのさ｡
Kids who don’t know when to quit can’t survive in this town.
(松平)ふぅ～…
財布もすっきりしたし➡
My wallet’s empty, so…
阿音ちゃん そろそろ お勘定を…｡
Ane-chan, the bill please.
What’re you talking about?
(阿音)なに言ってんの？
(松平)えっ!?
Your wallet may be empty, but your bank account isn’t, is it?
財布は ｶﾗでも
通帳は ｶﾗじゃねえだろうが！
早く おろしてこいよ！
Hurry and make a withdrawal. Or I’ll tell your wife everything.
奥さんに 全部ばらすぞ！
えっ…｡
(店長)あぁ いやいや…｡
Yes, you both were fantastic!
うん！ よく がんばった｡
阿音ちゃん お妙ちゃん｡
Ane-chan, Otae-chan. I have to say you both win the competition!
今回は 特別に ２人とも合格！
(阿音)いい勝負だったわ！
That was a great match.
(お妙)これからも この店
２人で盛り上げていきましょうね｡
From now on, let’s work together for the sake of the club!
♪♪～
[Kabukicho, town of greed]
[Tonight as always]
[Men and women replay the drama of love]
[Though they know it is]
[But a fleeting dream]
[They cannot escape]
[The fate of foolish men]
[Ah…]
[The morning sun is blinding again today]
おい…｡
Hey, What’s with the cheesy lyrics over our heads?
なんか上に変な詞みたいなのが
出てるんだけど…｡
(長谷川)
ごまかせると思ってるのか!!
Don’t try to trick me. That’s not going to settle anything!
それで まるく おさまると
思ってるのか!?
[Preview]
Wow! A monstrous guy has moved in!
“My neighbor Hedoro,” he looks so scary!
A florist by day, but he must be an alien conqueror by night!
The next episode… “Do Cherries Come from Cherry Trees?”
[Hedoro’s house shows up next door. Are those demon flowers for world conquest?]
[What is the fate of the Odd Jobs? Who must circulate the Neighborhood Notebook?]
♬～
(ﾃｰﾏ音楽)